Ethan Ferrier

Full Stack Web Developer

Redding, California
(503) 983-3730
https://ethanferrier.com
Fethanerrier@gmail.com
http://github.com/F-Ethan
http://www.linedin.com/in/
ethan-ferrier-891bb6155

PROJECTS

That Food Truck

— Frontend:

https://github.com/bethel-school-of-technology/that-food-truck-blog-frontend

—Backend:

https://github.com/bethel-school-of-technology/that-food-truck-blog-backend

This is a project that I worked on with three other Bethel tech Students for our final graduation project. This is a React application built as a website for a food truck. We also built in a Blog that the admin of the website can use to keep their users up to date on the latest news.

https://gracious-northcutt-ba993b.netlify.app

Built with React, React-Router-Dom, Axios, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB

Html, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, NoSql, Cors,

My Portfolio — https://github.com/F-Ethan/MyPortfolio

This is a website I made to showcase my abilities. It is a simple React Project that uses axios to list all my projects on GitHub and allows users to download my resume. You can find my portfolio website at, https://www.ethanferrier.com

Built with React, React-Router-Dom, Axios

Html, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

Web Tracker — https://github.com/F-Ethan/my_app

This is an online application for tracking maintenance history, rental location and rental dates for an equipment rental company. http://pursuit.pythonanywhere.com

https://www.ethanferrier.com

Built in python with Django

MySql, Html, CSS, JavaScript

Languages / Frameworks

Ionic *****

Angular ****

React ***

Python ****

Django ****

Flask **

jQuery, JavaScript (JS),

Bootstrap, CSS, HTML,

AJAX, Node, Express,

MongodB, Mongoose,

Passport, WebAPI,

Technologies

VisualStudio2015

Git

MVC, NPM, Bower, Atom

Dependency Injection

Heroku, netlify, mLab

EDUCATION

Bethel Tech Full Stack Web, Online— Javascript certificate

December 2019 – August 2020

Bethel School of Technology, powered by Apple's co-founder Steve Wozniak's Coding Bootcamp University (WozU) Acquired skills programming using Javascript, building web applications using Ionic, Angular, and React, database with MySql, and backend with Express. https://www.newsweek.com/insights/the-top-coding-schools-of-2019/bethel-school-technology (20 hours/ week)

Studied:

Angular, React, Ionic, jQuery, JavaScript (JS), Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, AJAX, Node, Express, MongodB, Mongoose, Passport, WebAPI,

Harvard's CS50 Web Programing with Python & Javascript

January 2019 - May 2019 (Online)

Learned to Develop Web applications with Python building with both Flask and Django and tying into MySql Databases. (20 hours/week)

Studied: Python, Javascript, MySql, Flask, DJango

EXPERIENCE

Bethel school, Redding—Intern to the Operations Manager

September 2016 - May 2017

Oversaw maintenance of Schools web application

Reconciled 20 years of the school's student records from two databases and all their paper records.

I streamlined the process using Excel and google sheets to sort through over 20,000 different Students and update all their pertinent information.

Worked with developers to update schools web application and to add new features.

Mike's Computer Repair, Long Beach, Wa— Computer Tech

June 2016 - August 2016

Virus removal, Screen repair, New computer setup

Food Maxx, Redding, CA— Front End Manager

April 2014 - April 2017

Supervised up to 20 employees at one time, Balanced Checkers' tills and store safe, Dealt with all unsatisfied customers.